

∞ futureproof

I was first introduced to programming in 2013, after deciding to found my own tech review site and complementary Android application. Subsequently, I have continued to broaden my technical skillset and knowledge of the highly dynamic sector. Being an avid problem solver and logical thinker, I savour the more binary and structured approach to solving issues that programming forces one to adopt. Other than programming and technology, I also enjoy learning about finance, astronomy and psychology, and my hobbies include cooking, listening to music and keeping up to date with all my favourite TV shows.

SUMMARY

I recently attained a 2:1 in Economics BSc from City, University of London and am currently training as a Full Stack Developer with futureproof. My degree has given me vast exposure to advanced mathematical concepts and complex problem solving — attributes that have proved vital during my futureproof course. I have always possessed a growing zeal for IT and technology. With the emergence of new and upcoming disruptive technologies, it is a particularly exciting time to be a tech enthusiast. This passion led me to apply for the futureproof course and I have thoroughly enjoyed learning to use new software and programming languages. My experiences working at Tata Consultancy Services and Willis Towers Watson over the last couple of years also introduced me to the basics of cloud computing and cyber security, through both completing research projects and presenting to various stakeholders.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Futureproof | Software Engineer | March 2020 - present

GitHub: www.github.com/eshan1799

- 13-week bootcamp covering the main areas of web development, including JavaScript, HTML/CSS, databases, and Python.
- Collaborated on numerous 1-week group projects, creating a trivia quiz, blog site and habit tracker using Jest and Enzyme
 to test.
- Debugged several programs in Python, React and SQL.

Tata Consultancy Services | Summer Analyst | June - July 2019

- Pitched to a potential client the upsides of integrating cloud services across their business verticals.
- Researched and suggested ways to incorporate TCS' new business offerings, e.g. IoT, Blockchain, into large global deals.

Willis Towers Watson | Summer Intern | June – July 2018

- Evaluated cybersecurity risk on client data platforms, contributing towards the 8% increase in cyber insurance revenues for June.
- Interpreted industry data and conducted a competitor analysis report, formulating data inputs using Excel and SQL.

The Tech Square | Founder | June 2013 - May 2018

- Created a tech review site and Google Play app offering users the latest updates on new technological advancements.
- Grew and retained a viewer base of 550 views per article and increased unique visitors on our site by an average annual rate of 160%.

EDUCATION

City, University of London | September 2016 - July 2019

- Economics (BSc Hons): Upper Second-Class Honours (2:1)
- Modules: Applied Econometrics, Intermediate Mathematical Methods, Financial Economics

Wallington County Grammar School | September 2010 – July 2017

- A-Levels: Mathematics (B), Economics (B), Computer Science (C)
- GCSEs: 5 A*s, 5 As, 2Bs (A* Mathematics, A English Language)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- Visual Basic.NET

Git Version Control

- JavaScript
 - React JS

HTML5 / CSS3

- SQL
- PostgreSQL / MongoDB
- Microsoft Office